<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Glossary on Seattle Urbanism Guide</title><link>/glossary/</link><description>Recent content in Glossary on Seattle Urbanism Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Housing &amp; Zoning</title><link>/glossary/housing-zoning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/glossary/housing-zoning/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="housing--zoning-terms">Housing &amp;amp; Zoning Terms&lt;a class="anchor" href="#housing--zoning-terms">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="adu-accessory-dwelling-unit">ADU (Accessory Dwelling Unit)&lt;a class="anchor" href="#adu-accessory-dwelling-unit">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A smaller, secondary home on the same lot as a main house. Think backyard cottages or basement apartments. Seattle has been loosening ADU rules since 2019 to allow more housing in single-family zones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Why it matters:&lt;/strong> ADUs are one of the gentlest ways to add housing in existing neighborhoods without changing their character dramatically. They&amp;rsquo;re a key part of Seattle&amp;rsquo;s strategy to add &amp;ldquo;missing middle&amp;rdquo; housing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transportation</title><link>/glossary/transportation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/glossary/transportation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="transportation-terms">Transportation Terms&lt;a class="anchor" href="#transportation-terms">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="complete-streets">Complete Streets&lt;a class="anchor" href="#complete-streets">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A street design approach that considers all users &amp;ndash; pedestrians, cyclists, transit riders, and drivers &amp;ndash; not just cars. May include wider sidewalks, protected bike lanes, bus-only lanes, and traffic calming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Why it matters:&lt;/strong> Seattle adopted a Complete Streets policy, and it shapes how SDOT designs road projects. When a street gets rebuilt, advocates can push for complete streets elements using this framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>See also:&lt;/strong> LOS, Vision Zero, Mode Share&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Land Use &amp; Planning</title><link>/glossary/land-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/glossary/land-use/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="land-use--planning-terms">Land Use &amp;amp; Planning Terms&lt;a class="anchor" href="#land-use--planning-terms">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="comprehensive-plan">Comprehensive Plan&lt;a class="anchor" href="#comprehensive-plan">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A city&amp;rsquo;s long-range plan for growth, land use, transportation, parks, and utilities. Required by Washington&amp;rsquo;s Growth Management Act. Seattle&amp;rsquo;s comp plan is updated on major cycles (most recently 2024) and guides zoning and investment decisions for 20+ years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Why it matters:&lt;/strong> The comprehensive plan is the single most important policy document for Seattle&amp;rsquo;s future. It determines where growth goes, what gets built, and how the city invests. The 2024 update was a major battleground over density, equity, and neighborhood change.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funding &amp; Policy</title><link>/glossary/funding-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/glossary/funding-policy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="funding--policy-terms">Funding &amp;amp; Policy Terms&lt;a class="anchor" href="#funding--policy-terms">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="impact-fees">Impact Fees&lt;a class="anchor" href="#impact-fees">#&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One-time charges on new development to pay for infrastructure (roads, parks, schools) needed to serve new residents. Seattle has been slow to adopt impact fees compared to other cities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Why it matters:&lt;/strong> Impact fees are a perpetual debate in Seattle. Developers argue they raise housing costs. Advocates say new development should pay for the infrastructure it requires. Whether and how Seattle implements impact fees affects both housing affordability and public services.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>